what's up guys welcome back to another
set and forget podcast so um I haven't
done a solo podcast probably like a
month right so I've had crazy people
back to back we just had Raja
um which blew up literally blew up um
appreciate you Roger from coming all the
way from Pakistan
um you know go coming over here getting
on the podcast and then the one before
that was my students uh most profitable
student he's gotten like about four or
five payouts from a funded account
making all his money so um they haven't
done a stolen one right so and I feel
like this is a good moment to do a solo
one because
um I like I feel you know I haven't
touched up on like a little bit of like
psychology and I promised you guys I was
gonna keep this psychology Series going
and you guys know like I don't like
missing any of my videos you guys know I
upload a video every single week whether
it's educational or uh podcasts
um appreciate all the love that we got
on the McDonald's video where I picked
up uh Josh from like literally out of
like the outside of Starbucks like I
left the drive through I picked them up
the amount of love
that I have gotten on that video is
insane like I personally myself I look
through every single one of those
comments and I'm going through these
comments and I'm just like bro I can't
keep up with them like I legit cannot
keep up going over thousands of comments
right like it's very hard to manage them
um but I appreciate it like it literally
that motivates me to get him back on a
part two three four and it generates my
motivation and it just like gives me
this energy to be creative for the next
one which I already have a crazy idea
for the next one I spoke with Josh I'm
like yo are you down to come back for a
part two he's like yeah so we're gonna
have a crazy part two coming soon so
make sure to stay tuned for that it's
gonna be uploaded a week from now so um
we're gonna start the video basically
right after we finish this recording so
this video
um is gonna go for you Josh and then for
everybody out there because I feel like
if the sooner you understand this the
sooner you shorten it you're losing
streak or you're losing curve as a
Trader because I feel like a lot of
people tend to struggle with this and
like the sooner you get the hang of it
the better right so I want to talk about
today which it is greed and fear
in training and then this is going to
lead to uh my next video which is going
to be risk management right but you guys
first have to understand this right so
these are the simplest to get through
because there is a structure on how to
control them like there's a very simple
solution for it like greed and fear
simply just emotion and things that you
go on like inside yourself and if you
control that based off of a trading plan
or some type of structure it completely
gets removed out of the equation because
when you have a checklist let's say I
need to take a trade that has x y z b
and if the trade only has X Y you know
that now the probabilities of this trade
going in your favor are a lot less than
before so you can't get greedy or have
fear have any type of emotion because
you know these other requirements aren't
there to take the trade right so that is
for sure the number one thing when it
comes to great and fear you need to have
a trading plan or some type of approach
that makes sense so we tend to have
green and this happens to to me still
sometimes today when I trade when I over
risk a little bit but I feel like this
is like the main beginning factor to a
lot of people that come into trading
they come in with the wrong mindset
that's because we want to make a
gazillion dollars the first time we open
up a trading account right whether it's
to pay off a car go on a vacation pay
your mortgage pay some debt off whatever
the case is you come into this wanting
to make an astronom uh astronomical
number with only a 500 deposit a
thousand dollar deposit and let's be
realistic those percentages are insane
it is not actually like yes it is
possible you could turn a thousand like
I've turned a thousand to like 15K but
that's unrealistic like percentages
right I go trading based off of
percentages like you're flipping that
account like 2030x that's like 20 000 on
a thousand dollar account like that is
not anything that is sustainable like
you need to have sustainability in this
business and you're not gonna have those
big numbers you're striving for it with
a 500 account it's just not gonna happen
it is possible but it's not going to
happen and that's why we get greedy
because we want to make all of these
numbers for with doing the least right
so that is not an investment strategy
another way we kind of get greedy when
we approach the markets and it still
happens to me sometimes it's probably
set and forget too much it's when like
let's say your trade is on its way to
its take profit and then again if you
were to have a trading plan this just
simply gets removed so let's stay in
your trading plan it says this trade is
Meant to hit a one to two risk to reward
when the trade reaches your take profit
of a one to two risk reward you close
your trade and you call it a day we tend
to get greedy because we're like bro to
be honest like two percent isn't that
much or a one to two risk reward isn't
that much people are out here catching
one to fives one to tens whatever so
what do we do we get greedy and they're
like you know what the center forget
this [__] so you set them forget it and
then yes now it reaches a one to three
one to four one to five and then you
close it but keep in mind you just broke
your trading plan you just got greedy
and complete broke your trading plan
so the result of this is when you go
into your next trade the same thing is
going to happen your trading plan says
take a one to two risk to reward trade
price goes hits your one to two risk to
reward trade and then you're gonna do
the same thing you're like you know what
sudden forget this [__] again and then
what happens it comes back to take you
at a break even so now greed emotion all
of this downward spiral thing is
happening due to the fact that you just
simply did not follow your trading plan
causing greed maybe you're not closing
your trade at where it's supposed to be
so this is a such key importance and it
rises your emotions for no reason simply
because you want more if your trading
plan says a one to two risk reward you
close it there and that's it does it
have a possibility of making one to ten
yes but then you figure out how to scale
in and how to get on another position
then there's no need to try and get the
most out of the trade even though it
keeps on going you stick to your trading
plan because that's obviously what it
works right so you can't bash yourself
for closing a trade in profit like if
it's season one to two take that and
that's it and I feel like that's kind of
where I am right now and when I work
with Josh I'm gonna really like explain
that [__] to him and be like look bro
you didn't know who I was
two weeks ago like I would have not put
you on to everything I'm about to put
you on yes you've came into the level up
HQ you're seeing the card you're seeing
all this crazy [__] but don't go after
this right now like I need you to
understand that there's levels to this
yes I'm making x amount on a trade on x
amount of an account but I need to
understand you're starting at a
different level that I am you're gonna
start at level one in order for you to
get to level two you have to do this and
then from level two you go to level
three you don't just jump from level one
to level ten because then you don't know
one what it takes to get from Level 10
to level 20 because now you're not
properly built up you don't have the
right foundation and then let's say you
go down a level because you make some
issues there's such a big gap that you
didn't know how you went up from level
five six seven eight nine like each
level that you go all the way right back
down to level one because you don't know
what it takes to go through each and
every single one of these levels so I
would definitely say when it comes to
not only trading to anything there's
levels to everything and then you
approach it by the level that you're
going so let's say for example that
right now you're in a position where
you're not a consistently profitable
Trader
don't aim to be a consistently
profitable Trader next week like I'm
gonna be here I'm gonna tell you guys
straight up that's just not gonna happen
I'm sorry but what I can guarantee you
is that in the next week you can be a
consistently not consistently losing
Trader meaning instead of losing every
single week back and back and back again
now you only probably lose one week
though the weaker break even the other
week you lose again the other week your
break even so now instead of just
completely going down you're kind of
like kind of like platoing on the way
like this to make something break even
after you figure out how to not continue
losing you don't aim to now make profits
now you aim to be around break even a
little bit above in profit now you need
to stay in the game before you were
losing blowing that account now the goal
is you want to stay in the game notice
how you're now in another level now in
this level the goal is to maintain this
level like you need to stay in the game
you need to stay either under five
percent above five percent this means
contain the account you want to continue
going as you trade after you master this
however time it takes it could take you
a month two three four it's different
for everybody we each have a different
drive we each have a different goal we
each have a different need for this
whenever you do reach that then you
reach your next level and now it's like
all right I'm good I already understand
I get what it takes to be a break even
Trader I get what it could happen if I
break my rules if I get greedy I would
lose my account lose all the money now
I'm going to aim to make consistent
profits but you're not going to be now
[__] every single week making profits
you'll probably make one week ten
percent another week you'll come back
down to three percent the next week
you'll probably be up five the following
week you'll be break even then the week
following you'll probably be down two
percent so now kind of instead of from
this graph going down then plateauing
now you're going up and now you're kind
of fluctuating up and then now you just
learn from those mistakes and you keep
it pushing but notice the journey look
how long it took me to explain this
imagine how long it actually takes to
apply in real life that's what I want to
explain to you guys that there is no
need to be greedy and then you need to
journal
all of these traits if you guys haven't
downloaded my free app it's completely
free up I'm not here sending you guys on
anything it's just download the app it's
free bro there's literally a journal in
there like I know my mistakes because I
adrenal them if you don't Journal your
trades how do you know what mistakes
you're doing like for example let's say
you work a job right now let's say you
work out whatever A Bank somebody comes
in and they deposit a thousand dollar
check and you mess it up the check gets
lost whatever the manager whoever and
the mother is going to come in and
they're going to be like yo you messed
up if you mess up again you're fired or
it's on you right when it comes to
trading nobody's going to hold you
accountable for that that person at that
job is holding you accountable so what
do you what are you you're on your tippy
toes every single time somebody comes in
deposit a check you know that you can't
mess this [__] up because it's on you so
you're I in your A game when it comes to
trading if you're not journaling your
own trades and holding yourself
accountable then who is nobody's going
to come in and tell you this probably
half the people around your circle don't
even know what you do they have
absolutely no idea what the hell you're
doing so so if you go to the free app
you literally there's a journal every
single trade you take you take a
screenshot you upload it in there and
then you write the description on why
you took the trade and then you save it
you come back at the end of the week and
then you're like oh you know what I
didn't wait for my entry signal oh
no what I was trading in a session where
there's no volume but you're finding all
of this stuff because you're journaling
your traits another trick that I did
when I started journaling my trades I
personally would write at the bottom how
I felt right after all of my confluences
everything how did I feel was I bored
was I tired that I want to feel involved
that I literally not give a [__] was I
angry like you just would type that in
and you got to be honest with yourself
there's nobody's like I'm not going to
go in there I'm not going to edit
because I don't know how you feel when
you take the trade right these are
internal emotions on how you feel so
that is something I highly highly
recommend you guys do because if you
don't hold yourself accountable nobody
else is you're responsible for your
success and if you didn't do it nobody
else is going to do it for you right so
finishing degree topic next is fear and
it kind of goes back
um to some things that I've talked about
in another podcast
the majority of the people we're fearful
of people's opinion were fearful of
people like we're fearful of being
different standing out because then
obviously we'll get judged and then
we're feared by making mistakes like bro
like I remember like
I remember when I was posting charts on
my Instagram
probably like three four years ago bro I
was getting roasted like people were
telling me like yo you're a clown that's
just never gonna work and like that [__]
kind of didn't mess with me at the time
and then you know like that like those
things kind of like eat up some people I
don't want to say that like they don't
have the right mindset but like bro why
do you care about these people opinions
like that [__] really does not matter at
all so I feel like fear is a very big
factor into greed because we want to
make that 100K a week so we tell all
these people that are causing us fear
hey look this [__] is real it does work
so bro it doesn't matter you do this for
yourself don't do it for anybody like
when I made my first couple big days I
really didn't tell anybody other than my
inner circle at the time and even then
they still gave me hate or it kind of
like they had they had an opinion I'm
like bro you don't even understand what
I had to do to make this like you know
what I mean so definitely when it comes
to fear that is something that I
personally would not even consider uh
like this just nothing to that like I
could go on a couple examples and
explanations but it's simple cut off
fear and then don't let greed drive your
purpose to make money to show those In
Fear And if you're fearful just it's
okay like it's part of the game like I
need you guys to understand that
um I do want to touch up on I mean you
know what I'm going to save these other
because I have I have so much Gems like
right here like right in front of me but
I'm gonna save them for the next podcast
where it's going to be strictly risk
management and how I do my approach to
the trading because you guys see it on
the track record oh yeah and my free app
there's I literally show a track like my
track record of all the signals that I
send
like there's another like there's an
actual risk management approach like I
don't just go on there every single day
click a couple buttons and that [__]
happens like like there's actual money
management strategies like you need to
learn how to manage money before you
even trade like let's say like why do
why do most of the people that win the
lottery why do most of them lose it I
think it's like an actual stat like in
the first two years they legit lose it
all they spend it all because they have
no money management so this is the same
thing with trading a lot of us don't
have money management neither did I at
one point had to learn it so um you're
putting up the the stat yeah so for sure
I'm going to
save all these gems for the next video
so make sure to stay tuned the next one
is going to be risk management on how
exactly I um do my approach to the
market so I I want to appreciate you
guys Josh if you're watching this if
you're not watching this you better be
watching this stay tuned for the next
video along with all of you guys
um that watch the McDonald's video I got
a bunch of more gems coming and I
appreciate it I appreciate all of you
guys watching the video I love you Tien
make sure to like comment subscribe and
see you guys at the top